<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Hylu Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Hylu Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 02:07:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pianotypes Devlog 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/10/pianotypes-devlog-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 02:07:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/10/pianotypes-devlog-5/</guid>
      <description>Not many code changes as of late but I&amp;rsquo;ve been more active on one of the packages I&amp;rsquo;m using to play sound, smplr. It&amp;rsquo;s such an amazing package for playing instrument sounds with an incredibly simple and powerful api. Kudos to danigb.
A bunch of new changes were made recently that have added some awesome features as well as some bugs I found while using them.
Note Scheduling Throughput The first change was a tweak to note scheduling that fixes an issue of the web audio getting overloaded and introducing lot&amp;rsquo;s of static.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Useful Linear Algebra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/09/useful-linear-algebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 12:17:47 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/09/useful-linear-algebra/</guid>
      <description>Dot Product Find the interior angle between two vectors $$ A\cdot B = |A||B|cos\theta $$
$$ \theta = \arccos(\dfrac{A\cdot B}{|A||B|}) $$
$$ where\ A\cdot B = A_x \times A_y + B_x \times B_y $$
Cross Product Get perpendicular vector from two vectors Find area created by two vectors (for 2D, parallelogram area, for 3D, parallelepiped area) This is the magnitude of perpendicular vector Matrix Multiplication There is a formula for calculating the resultant matrix from a matrix multiplication.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pianotypes Devlog 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/pianotypes-devlog-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 21:51:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/pianotypes-devlog-4/</guid>
      <description>Not too much to report.
I had the realization that I can pause the scheduled notes by suspending the AudioContext since they depend on the context&amp;rsquo;s timer. It&amp;rsquo;d be pretty easy to add pause functionality. The only caveat is that if I pause the AudioContext, than all sound from the piano is also paused. Perhaps I could code in a notice to resume the timer given the user inputs a key press but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to resume the context on every key press.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reviving Tabby Sort</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/reviving-tabby-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 22:23:06 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/reviving-tabby-sort/</guid>
      <description>A couple years ago I made a little extension for chrome to organize and sort tabs by url domains. It was really quick and crudely designed and since I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even a Chrome user, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think too much about improving it. Fast forward to now, I decided to do exactly that.
Looking at old code Actually the code was mostly better than I expected, other than some variable naming and redundant lines, I didn&amp;rsquo;t see much need to rewrite it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pianotypes Devlog 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/pianotypes-devlog-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 09:29:07 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/pianotypes-devlog-3/</guid>
      <description>Today I spent some time working on getting the instructions dialogues up. I originally planned on creating a secondary overlay window that pops up given a trigger. Very similar to how to the toast notifications work but instead with a much larger area. The only problem with that is I wanted a clean way to inject custom html into the dialogue box depending on who triggers it. In the case of the toast notification I just pass it a string which is fine given it&amp;rsquo;s only suppose to be a sure notifier anyways.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pianotypes Devlog 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/pianotypes-devlog-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 13:18:35 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/pianotypes-devlog-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a bit more than late for a second devlog but I figured there&amp;rsquo;s no better thing to call this. I originally made this blog for the purposes of short and sweet devlogs but my recent posts have been bit larger than what I originally intended. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping with this log to bring that focus back down to just that.
Since my previous post, I&amp;rsquo;ve done a lot of fine tuning of the UI and functionality of the site.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisting Pianotypes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/revisting-pianotypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 17:50:32 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/revisting-pianotypes/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished a course in deep learning and wanted to took a look at a few ways I could apply my knowledge to. The idea the came to me was to create an ai music generation model and feed it into my old pianotypes app. Simple right!
It&amp;rsquo;s all broken So I booted up my old, dusty, untouched, forgotten, delapidated, abused, ramshackled, repository, and lo and behold, I can&amp;rsquo;t get it to run.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Svelte Reactive Classes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/svelte-reactive-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 20:29:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/svelte-reactive-classes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on migrating my old PianoTypes project over from Vue to Svelte. So far the syntax has been much cleaner to use and has been an overall a great experience. My first and primary pain point thus far has been implementing a global reactive state for the piano.
The Problem In Vue, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to add a reactive wrapper to any object. In my case, I had created a class containing all of the piano data and property methods so all I had to do was wrap this class in the wrapper and state is maintained across all instances of my piano class.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JS Modules in Hugo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/js-modules-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 07:57:33 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/js-modules-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>While writing this blog, I&amp;rsquo;ve been constantly finding a need to include various JavaScript libraries such as graphics libraries or text processors. I love the simplicity of Markdown but sometimes it can be really helpful to include more meaningful content and visuals to better illustrate a certain topic or idea.
My most recent endeavor was adding an easy way to render shaders within each of posts which turned out to be a more painful task than I originally anticipated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Matrix Rotations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/3d-matrix-rotations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 02:03:50 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/3d-matrix-rotations/</guid>
      <description>Rotation is one such transformation and that can be achieved by locking the desired axes of rotation and transforming the rest of the axes by \(sin\) and \(cos\).
Intuition of 3x3Matrix Transformations 3x3 matrices can be used to bend the coordinate space in 3 dimensions, effectively allowing any desired transformations to objects in that space.
As the coordinate space is being transformed, it&amp;rsquo;s helpful breaking up the matrix into its unit vectors</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Quaternions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/quaternion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 10:37:52 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/quaternion/</guid>
      <description>When describing rotations of an object, the typical way would be through linear algebra and trigonometry. However, similarly to how complex numbers can be used to describe rotations in 2D, quaternions allow efficient and more pragmatic methods describing rotations in 3D.
How It&amp;rsquo;s Done With Trigonometry Depending on the framework or software using, a lot of the work is already done for you with API available to you to perform rotations on shapes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Character Unity Setup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/3d_character_unity_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 10:54:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/3d_character_unity_setup/</guid>
      <description>I followed this tutorial https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bXNFxQpp2qk&amp;amp;list=PLwyUzJb_FNeQrIxCEjj5AMPwawsw5beAy&amp;amp;index=3
Adding a 3D Character Animation States Unity has it&amp;rsquo;s own skeleton rigging system called Mecanim.
To add animations to a character, you first need to add an animator component to your character model and then create a character controller object and link it to the component. Double clicking the controller will then open up a panel to handle state transitions between animations.
There you can add each of the states you want to transition your model to and from.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Folder Structure and Making Mistakes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/other/folder_structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 15:44:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/other/folder_structure/</guid>
      <description>When using a programming engine or framework, one of the things I get stuck on the most is how to organize all the directories and files for a project. Every technology has its own separate ethos when it comes to the separation of concerns. It&amp;rsquo;s such an important part in order to not have a growing project becoming a nightmare for other&amp;rsquo;s to work with, or even yourself after spending some time away from it.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
