<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pianotypes on Hylu Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/pianotypes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pianotypes on Hylu Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 02:07:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/pianotypes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pianotypes Devlog 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/10/pianotypes-devlog-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 02:07:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/10/pianotypes-devlog-5/</guid>
      <description>Not many code changes as of late but I&amp;rsquo;ve been more active on one of the packages I&amp;rsquo;m using to play sound, smplr. It&amp;rsquo;s such an amazing package for playing instrument sounds with an incredibly simple and powerful api. Kudos to danigb.
A bunch of new changes were made recently that have added some awesome features as well as some bugs I found while using them.
Note Scheduling Throughput The first change was a tweak to note scheduling that fixes an issue of the web audio getting overloaded and introducing lot&amp;rsquo;s of static.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pianotypes Devlog 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/pianotypes-devlog-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 21:51:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/pianotypes-devlog-4/</guid>
      <description>Not too much to report.
I had the realization that I can pause the scheduled notes by suspending the AudioContext since they depend on the context&amp;rsquo;s timer. It&amp;rsquo;d be pretty easy to add pause functionality. The only caveat is that if I pause the AudioContext, than all sound from the piano is also paused. Perhaps I could code in a notice to resume the timer given the user inputs a key press but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to resume the context on every key press.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pianotypes Devlog 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/pianotypes-devlog-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 09:29:07 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/pianotypes-devlog-3/</guid>
      <description>Today I spent some time working on getting the instructions dialogues up. I originally planned on creating a secondary overlay window that pops up given a trigger. Very similar to how to the toast notifications work but instead with a much larger area. The only problem with that is I wanted a clean way to inject custom html into the dialogue box depending on who triggers it. In the case of the toast notification I just pass it a string which is fine given it&amp;rsquo;s only suppose to be a sure notifier anyways.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pianotypes Devlog 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/pianotypes-devlog-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 13:18:35 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/old/dev/pianotypes-devlog-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a bit more than late for a second devlog but I figured there&amp;rsquo;s no better thing to call this. I originally made this blog for the purposes of short and sweet devlogs but my recent posts have been bit larger than what I originally intended. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping with this log to bring that focus back down to just that.
Since my previous post, I&amp;rsquo;ve done a lot of fine tuning of the UI and functionality of the site.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
